Guide to the Gene Feist papers
The New York Public Library. Billy Rose Theatre Division.
Gene Feist papers
1930s-2000
1944-1997
*T-Mss 1997-010
18264
Feist, Gene
The New York Public Library. Billy Rose Theatre Division. New York Public Library for the Performing Arts, Dorothy and Lewis B. Cullman Center 40 Lincoln Center Plaza, New York, NY 10023-7498
28.29 linear feet 72 boxes
Gene Feist (1923-) is an American artistic director, playwright, producer, director and teacher. In 1965 he co-founded the Roundabout Theatre Company, of which he served as Artistic Director until 1988. The Gene Feist Papers document the personal and professional life Gene Feist and the history of the Roundabout Theatre Company. Types of materials in this collection include personal correspondence, production files, topical files, drafts of scripts, photographs, playbills and programs, reviews, publicity materials, business files and personal ephemera.
Gene Feist (1923-) is an American artistic director, playwright, producer, director, teacher and co-founder of the Roundabout Theatre Company. Feist was born in New York City on January 16, 1923. In 1951 he graduated from Carnegie Institute of Technology with a BFA in Directing and Playwriting. The following year he received an MA from New York University in Educational Theatre. Over the next few years he studied with Lee Strasberg at the American Theatre Wing. In 1957, Feist married Kathe Snyder (Elizabeth Owens), an actress who frequently performed in early Roundabout Theatre productions. They have two daughters, Nicole and Gena.
During the 1950s and early 1960s, Feist worked for several different theatre companies, serving as Producer and Resident Playwright for the Two by Four Theatre; as General Manager and Production Coordinator at the Stamford Playhouse; as Founder and Executive Producer of the Renata Theatre; as General Manager and Publicist at the Sharon Playhouse; and as Producer and Artistic Director of the New Theatre Nashville. From 1962-1964 he was a drama critic for the Chelsea-Clinton News. He was also writing constantly during this period and he directed his plays Lust for a Nightingale and A Toy for the Clowns at the Actors' Studio, and Wretched the Lionhearted at the East End Theatre.
Feist and his wife, actress Elizabeth Owens, conceived the idea of the nonprofit Roundabout Theatre Company in 1965. Feist wanted to do classic plays by authors like Ibsen and Shaw and thought that a subscription series at an affordable price would be of interest to New Yorkers. Roundabout's first production of Strindberg's The Father was presented in a 150-seat theatre in the basement of a supermarket in Chelsea. In that first season, the company had four hundred subscribers who paid only $5.00 for three plays. In their early years, the Roundabout also produced original plays, which attracted well-known actors such as Kim Hunter, Vincent Price, Irene Worth, Tammy Grimes, Malcolm McDowell, and Philip Bosco.
While Roundabout was growing artistically, the company was struggling financially, filing for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in 1978. By 1983, the company had an accumulated $2.5 million deficit on a $1.5 million budget. Todd Haimes, came on board as Managing Director. Just two weeks later, the Board voted to close the theatre due to financial troubles. Board member Christian C. Yegen agreed to write checks to cover the payroll, and within two years, Roundabout emerged from Chapter 11 protection. In 1984, Roundabout staged its most acclaimed production up to that time, Peter Nichols' A Day in the Death of Joe Egg starring Jim Dale and Stockard Channing. The production moved to Broadway where it won the 1985 Tony®, Drama Desk, and Outer Critics Circle Awards for Outstanding Revival. Roundabout's growth continued with the opening of the 17th Street Theatre on January 30, 1985 with The Playboy of the Western World, starring Kate Burton and Ken Marshall.
In 1989, Gene Feist retired and Todd Haimes was appointed Artistic Director, but Feist continued to work with the Roundabout in the official capacity of Founder and Consultant. During the five years that followed, Roundabout's productions were nominated for 79 awards, including Tonys®, Drama Desks, Outer Critics Circle and Olivier Awards. Harold Pinter's The Homecoming was followed by other acclaimed productions, such as Friedrich Durrenmatt's The Visit with Jane Alexander and Eugene O'Neill's Anna Christie starring Natasha Richardson and Liam Neeson, which won the 1993 Tony, Outer Critics Circle and Drama Desk Awards for Best Revival. Later that season, Haimes expanded the theatre's mission to produce musicals, and Roundabout introduced its Great American Musical series with, She Loves Me, directed by Scott Ellis and choreographed by Rob Marshall, which successfully transferred to Broadway and was also produced in London, where it received five Olivier awards. In September 1995 the Roundabout produced the American premiere of Harold Pinter's Moonlight, starring Jason Robards and Blythe Danner. Roundabout had some of their biggest hits with the Tony Award® winning revivals of Cabaret, starring Natasha Richardson and Alan Cumming and Stephen Sondheim and John Weidman's musical Assassins, directed by Joe Mantello. Since 1965, the Roundabout has grown from a small, off-Broadway theatre into one of the leading cultural institutions in New York City.
*From www.roundabouttheatre.org/history, retrieved 12/23/2010
The Gene Feist Papers document the personal and professional life of American artistic director, playwright, producer, director, and teacher Gene Feist and the history of the Roundabout Theatre Company, one of New York's most acclaimed and successful non-for-profit theatre companies. Types of materials in this collection include personal correspondence, production files, topical files, drafts of scripts, photographs, playbills and programs, reviews, publicity materials, business files and personal ephemera.
Series I, Gene Feist consists of materials pertaining to Feist's personal and professional life apart from his work with the Roundabout Theatre Company. Feist's pre-Roundabout professional activities include his work as a playwright, critic, teacher, and director. This material includes correspondence with colleagues such as the renowned acting teachers Yale Wexler and Stella Adler, the latter of whom was also a longtime close personal friend of Feist and his wife. Correspondence with other friends includes, most substantially, letters to and from Thelma Laird Magers Lauer. Feist dated her in the 1940s and they remained lifelong friends after their marriages to other people. His extensive correspondence with her, over a period of fifty years, provides an invaluable autobiographical documentation of his adult life. Other correspondents include Feist's wife, Kathe, and their daughters, Gena and Nicole.
Feist's Writings consist mainly of drafts of plays Feist wrote, adapted or translated and his articles and reviews for the Chelsea-Clinton News. Other writings include drafts and excerpts from novels, short stories, and poems, his thesis, and a proposed nonfiction work on the history of the American theatre. There are also files and scrapbooks concerning, regional and community theatres, schools, and camps where Feist served as director, artistic director or producer. These include New Rochelle High School, Manitou-wabing Camp of Fine Arts in Parry Sound, Ontario and the New Theatre Nashville. There are also subject files on people, places, productions, schools as well as significant topics/events, such as Feist's teaching certifications.
Feist also worked on Theatron: A Festival of Four Staged Readings of New Israeli Plays, produced at the Joseph Papp Public Theatre, in association with the Israeli Ministry of Culture and Education. Of particular interest are several scripts of plays, in translation, by Israeli authors submitted to the Theatron for inclusion in the festival
Series II: Roundabout Theatre Company contains institutional files of the Roundabout, from its founding in 1965 through 2000. Materials include an extensive collection of production shots from Roundabout productions, as well as playbills, programs and posters. Other production files include scripts, correspondence, set designs and publicity materials. Company records include subject files on individuals and organizations with which the Roundabout had contact; business files, including contracts, negotiations, legal and financial records. Also included are administrative files on classes, conservatories and conferences run by the Roundabout, including transcripts of classes taught by Feist. Scrapbooks of articles, correspondence, designs and photographs document the Roundabout's moves over the years between seven different theatres in Chelsea and Midtown. The production shots, posters and playbills in this collection are an extraordinary resource, visually documenting the Roundabout's history from its inception through the 1990s. Although Feist stepped down as Artistic Director in 1988, this collection also covers the following 10 years, when Feist was still actively involved in the Roundabout's productions as a consultant.
The Gene Feist papers are organized in the following series:
Series I: Gene Feist, circa 1930-1996
Series II: Roundabout Theatre Company, 1965-2000
This collection was donated to the New York Public Library by Gene Feist in 2004.
This collection includes audiocasettes.
Feist, Gene; Adler, Stella; Magers, Thelma Laird; Wexler, Yale; Roundabout Theatre Company; Dramatists, American; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States -- 20th century; Photographs; Playbills; Scripts (documents); Sound recordings; Playwrights; Theatrical producers and directors
- Series I: Gene Feist, circa 1930-1996; 41 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1944-1992
    - Adler, Stella (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
    - Beresford-Clark, Lady (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Blumberg, Ellie Simon (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Burliuk, David (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Calcango, Lawrence (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chall, David (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Delighter, Harry (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dunn, Edward (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Feist, Gena (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Feist, Kathe (a.k.a. Elizabeth Owens) (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
    - Feist, Nicole (Nikki) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - France, Richard (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fried, Michael (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Garber, Fern (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Gassman, Morton (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hoguet, Tom (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Linnard, Stephen (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Magers, Thelma Laird (Box 3, Folder 1-16)
    - Magers, Thelma Laird (Box 4, Folder 1-13)
    - Magers, Thelma Laird (Box 5, Folder 1-8)
    - Magers, Thelma Laird (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Pazer, Mitzi and Perry (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Phillips, Lois (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Rice, Drury (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Satumi, Katsingo and Lu family (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Senter, Evelyn (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Wexler, Yale (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Wurtzel, Stuart (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Writings, 1949-1991
    See also: Scrapbooks
    - Plays
      - Adventures of a Sensitive Butcher (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - The Bargain Hunter (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - A Bride, a Son, a Groom (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Building Blocks (Box 7, Folder 4-7)
      - Casey and the Bat (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
      - Chasing Rainbows (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Cheri (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Civil War play (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Climb a Golden Stair (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Coming Through (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Coney Island (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Dirty Faces (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Everywhere I Roam (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Falling Off Place (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Fifty Grand (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Gangster story (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Golden Stranger (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Governor's play (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
      - The Great Gatsby (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Hedda Gabbler (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Hollywood script (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - How Do You Spell Murder? (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Ideas for plays (Box 8, Folder 13-18)
      - James Joyce's Dublin (Box 8, Folder 19-22)
      - James Joyce's Dublin (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
      - Jet Heron (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Jocasta and Oedipus (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
      - Joseph Burk (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - The Lady from Maxim's (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Lady Trouble (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Larchmoor is Not the World (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Leftover Life to Live (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - A Little Waltz, a Little Tango (Box 9, Folder 13-17)
      - Lust for the Nightingale (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
      - Lust for the Nightingale (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
      - Martha's play (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
      - Nightclub act (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Off-Broadway play (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Old Ones (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Picnic on a Battlefield (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Rabbits (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Relative Strangers (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
      - The Roaring Boy (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Scenario for Violence (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Sixty Something (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Sparta is Not the World (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Spiritualism play (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Tiger in the Parlor (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Time Out (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Today Just Like Tomorrow (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
      - Toward No Spring (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - A Toy for the Clowns (Box 11, Folder 8-11)
      - Viva (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - We Arrive as Strangers (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
      - Weber and Fields (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
      - Welfare play (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Witchcraft (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Woman of Distinction (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Wretched the Lionhearted (Box 13, Folder 4-7)
      - You Need a Pogrom to Tell a Rabbi (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Poetry (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Reviews (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Short stories and novels
      - Act of Love (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Bleecker Street (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Coney Island (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Donna (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Firecrackers (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - 43 Pipes and Bogart's Grave (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Franz Swann (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Glenn (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Leonard (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Oriental Atelier (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Saturday Night (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Stories (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Various
      - History of the American Theatre (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Queen Elizabeth II (Cruise Ship) Mystery (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Thesis, The Dance of Death: August Strindberg (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Regional theatres, camps and schools, 1945-1993
    - Carnegie Institute of Technology (Box 16, Folder 1-15)
    - Manitou-wabing Camp of Fine Arts (Box 16, Folder 16-19)
    - Manitou-wabing Camp of Fine Arts (Box 17, Folder 1-8)
    - Manitou-wabing Camp of Fine Arts (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - New Rochelle High School (Box 17, Folder 9-28)
    - New Rochelle High School (Box 18, Folder 1-9)
    - New Theatre Nashville (Box 18, Folder 10-14)
    - New Theatre Nashville (Box 19, Folder 1-22)
    - New Theatre Nashville (Box 20, Folder 1-9)
    - Renata Theatre, Inc. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Sharon Playhouse (Box 20, Folder 11-16)
    - Stamford Playhouse/Argo Productions (Box 20, Folder 17-21)
    - State College, Pennsylvania (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Valley Community Theatre (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Subject files, 1947-1995
    - Actor's Studio, The (Box 21, Folder 3-11)
    - American National Theatre and Academy (ANTA) (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - American Theatre Wing (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Biographies (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Civil Service commission (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Certification (Teaching of Speech in Secondary Schools, New Jersey) (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Certification (New York) (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Columbia University (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Family (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Feist, Kathe, nee Snyder (Elizabeth Owens) (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Hungary (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Katz, Harvey (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Madden, Donald (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Montana State College (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - New York School of Printing (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - New York University (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Profile of Feist by Bill Stevenson (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Regosin Institute (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sackville-West, V. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Warhol, Andy (Donna De Salvo) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - West Point (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Who's Afraid of Virginia Wolf? (Edward Albee) (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Wills (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbooks, circa 1930-1965
    - Actors and actresses (Feist fan books) (Box 23, Folder 10-12)
    - Actors and actresses (Feist fan books) (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Babes in Arms, New Faces, Good News, Bayonne (Box 24)
    - Biggstuff (Box 63, Folder 3)
      Newsletter of Biggs Army Airfield, Corporal Eugene Feist, editor
    - Bye Bye Birdie (Box 25)
    - Carnegie Tech (Box 62)
    - Hillside High School-International Theatre & Argo (Box 26)
    - Jocasta and Oedipus (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Manitou-wabing Camp of Fine Arts (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Manitou-wabing Camp of Fine Arts (Box 28)
    - New Faces (Box 29)
    - New Theatre Nashville (Box 30-32)
    - The Pajama Game, Sharon Playhouse (Box 33)
    - Stamford Playhouse, Sugar and Spice (Box 34)
    - Two by Four, Wretched the Lionhearted (Box 35)
    - Writings, various productions (Box 36)
  - Appointment books, journals and address books, 1982-1996 (Box 37, Folder 1-4)
  - Theatron: A Festival of Four Staged Readings of New Israeli Plays (Box 38-39)
    In association with the Israeli Ministry of Culture and Education, at the Joseph Papp Public Theatre.
- Series II: Roundabout Theatre Company, 1965-2000; 30 boxes
  - Administrative files, 1984-1988
    - Actors, designers and directors, lists (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Feist, Gene (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Haimes, Todd (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - History of Roundabout, early years (Box 40, Folder 4-6)
    - Meetings (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Seifter, Harvey (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Stationary (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Awards and tributes, 1987-1994 (Box 40, Folder 10-17)
    Includes Roundabout gala
  - Contracts, legal negotiations and finances, 1976-1993
    - Babitt, Judge Roy (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Bankruptcy/Chapter 11 (Box 41, Folder 2-5)
    - By-laws (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Equity workshop dispute (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Feigner, Ron (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Finances (Box 42, Folder 2-3)
    - Fried, Michael (Box 42, Folder 4-5)
    - Incorporation (Box 42, Folder 6-7)
    - Liabilities (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - NYCA protest campaign (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Original contributors and first subscribers (Box 71, Folder 1-2)
    - Yaegan, Chris (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Various (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Conservatories, conferences, classes, 1976-1996
    - Conservatory at St. Peter's, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 5-10)
    - Lectures (Box 43, Folder 11-12)
    - Masterclass, Feist (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Scene study class, Feist (Box 43, Folder 14-15)
    - Writers' conference, Santa Barbara (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Costumes designs, 1979 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    Includes The Learned Ladies, Denver Center Theatre
  - Notes, 1970-1990
    - Daily notes (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Directors' notes (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Photographs and slides of productions, 1967-1973, undated
    - Photographs
      - 1967-1969, Scrapbooks (Box 64, Volume 1-2)
      - 1969-1970, Scrapbook (Box 65, Volume 1)
      - 1970-1971, Scrapbooks (Box 66, Volume 1-2)
      - 1971-1973, Scrapbooks (Box 67, Volume 1-2)
      - Ah, Wilderness, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Ah, Wilderness, 1983 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - All My Sons, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - All My Sons, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - American Gothics, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - American Gothics, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Arms and the Man, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - Awake and Sing, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - The Bacchae, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - The Bond, 1967-1968 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - The Bloodknot, 1980 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - The Browning Version, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Brownstone, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Bunker Reveries, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - The Burnt Flowerbed, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - The Burnt Flowerbed, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Candida, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - The Caretaker, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - The Caretaker, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 18)
      - The Chalk Garden, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Chas. Abbott and Son, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Chas. Abbott and Son, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - The Cherry Orchard, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - The Cherry Orchard, 1976 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - The Circle, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - The Circle, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Clarence, 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Clarence, 1975-1976 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Come Back Little Sheba, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Conditions of Agreement, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Conditions of Agreement, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - The Country Girl, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - The Creditors, 1971-1972 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - The Crucible, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Dance of Death, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Dandy Dick, 1987 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - The Dark at the Top of the Stairs, 1979-1980 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - A Day in the Death of Joe Egg, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Dear Liar, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - Dear Mr. G, 1975-1976 (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Desire Under the Elms, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Don Juan in Hell, 1980-1981 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - Duet for One, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Endgame, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Endgame, 1976 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Enemy of the People, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - Enrico IV, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - The Entertainer, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - The Father, 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - The Father, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - Fallen Angels, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - Family Business, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 26)
      - The Fox, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 27)
      - Ghosts, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Ghosts, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Hamlet, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Heartbreak House, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Hedda Gabler, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - The Holly and the Ivy, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - The Homecoming, 1991-1992 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - How He Lied to Her Husband, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1967-1968 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Inadmissible Evidence, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - James Joyce's Dubliners, 1975 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - James Joyce's Dubliners, 1975 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Jeeves Takes Charge, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Jocasta and Oedipus, 1969-1970 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - John Gabriel Boorkman, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Journey's End, 1968-1969 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - The Killing of Sister George, 1983-1984 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - King Lear, 1968-1969 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - King Lear, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - King Lear, 1990-1991 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - The Knack, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 19)
      - The Knack, 1983 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - The Lady from Maxim's, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - The Learned Ladies, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 21)
      - Little Eyolf, 1979 (Box 46, Folder 22)
      - Look Back in Anger, 1980 (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - Look Back in Anger, 1980 (Box 68, Folder 16)
      - Love and Intrigue, 1975-1976 (Box 46, Folder 24)
      - Macbeth, 1969-1970 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Macbeth, 1969-1970 (Box 68, Folder 17)